<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - Tiexin Guo</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/</link><description>All Posts | Tiexin Guo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Brief History of the DMCA</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/dmca-takedowns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Tiexin Guo | 郭铁心</author><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/dmca-takedowns/</guid><description>Note This article is orignally published at GitGuardian Blog. What is DMCA? The DMCA is short for the Digital Millennium Copyright Act. On Oct 12, 1998, the US Congress passed the DMCA, which amended U.S. copyright law to address important issues of the relationship between copyright and the internet. It was signed into law by President Clinton on Oct 28, 1998. What Exactly Does It Mean? I know, the term</description></item><item><title>How To Setup Your Jenkins Pipeline in K8s with Git Secrets Leak Scan and Docker Image Scan</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/devsecops-jenkins-in-k8s-with-secret-scan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Tiexin Guo | 郭铁心</author><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/devsecops-jenkins-in-k8s-with-secret-scan/</guid><description>This blog post is first published at GitGuardian blog. Disclaimer: this tutorial goes all the way through setting up Jenkins in a Kubernetes minikube cluster, if you&amp;rsquo;re only interested in the Jenkinsfile, jump to the last part! 0 GitGuardian and ggshield ggshield is a CLI application that runs in your local environment or in a CI environment to help you detect more than 350 types of secrets, as well as</description></item><item><title>On DevOps: 1. What It Is</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/on-devops-1-what-it-is/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Tiexin Guo | 郭铁心</author><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/on-devops-1-what-it-is/</guid><description><![CDATA[Note: opinions are my own. They don&rsquo;t represent my current company or any previous companies I&rsquo;ve worked for. Note 2: recently, my colleague published a blog post (in Chinese, here&rsquo;s the link if you are interested). I like this post, but I&rsquo;d like to share more with you on the topic of DevOps. So I decided to publish a miniseries (7 episodes planned) on DevOps. Here&rsquo;s the first article. Note]]></description></item><item><title>9 Extraordinary Terraform Best Practices That Will Change Your Infra World</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/9-terraform-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Tiexin Guo | 郭铁心</author><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/9-terraform-best-practices/</guid><description><![CDATA[Note This article is orignally published at GitGuardian Blog. Before you quickly glance over the title and think &ldquo;Oh god, yet another tutorial on how to give proper names to variables, how to use modules, how to manage states; nothing I haven&rsquo;t already know&rdquo; then close the tab right away, let me assure you this: this article is none of those. This &ldquo;best practices&rdquo; article aims to tell you something]]></description></item><item><title>Dagger (the CI/CD Tool, not the Knife) In-Depth - Everything You Need to Know (as of Apr 2022)</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/dagger-in-depth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Tiexin Guo | 郭铁心</author><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/dagger-in-depth/</guid><description><![CDATA[1 What is Dagger? TL;DR: Dagger runs your CI/CD pipelines locally in a Docker container, and can run the container in any CI environment (as long as that CI can run a container, of course.) Do you want the long answer to this million-dollar question? It&rsquo;s hard to answer, honestly. News is calling it a &ldquo;DevOps platform&rdquo;; the VC that funded Dagger even called it a &ldquo;DevOps operating system.&rdquo; But,]]></description></item><item><title>Creating a DevStream (dtm) Plugin for Anything</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/creating-a-dtm-plugin-for-anything/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Tiexin Guo | 郭铁心</author><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/creating-a-dtm-plugin-for-anything/</guid><description><![CDATA[Yes, the title of this post isn&rsquo;t bluffing: you can actually create a plugin for just about anything that takes your fancy. In my previous article, I walked you guys through DevStream&rsquo;s codebase. If you haven&rsquo;t read it yet, here&rsquo;s a quick link for you: Hello, world! In this blog, we will walk you through the steps of creating a DevStream plugin from scratch with an example. What is DevStream]]></description></item><item><title>Hello, World!</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Tiexin Guo | 郭铁心</author><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/hello-world/</guid><description><![CDATA[Hello, and welcome to the DevStream blog! In this very first &ldquo;hello world&rdquo; post, I will: give you a high-level picture of how DevStream functions; walk you through our codebase; explain briefly how to create your own plugin. If you haven&rsquo;t heard of DevStream yet, please have a quick glance over our README. Without further adieu, let&rsquo;s get started. TL;DR Too bad, there isn&rsquo;t one. But don&rsquo;t close the tab]]></description></item></channel></rss>