<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Tiexin Guo</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Tiexin Guo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>10 Best DevOps Tools for Start-ups</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/10-devops-tools-for-startups/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/10-devops-tools-for-startups/</guid><description>OK. You are in a small start-up, and you want to move fast. To move fast, you will need automation instead of doing stuff manually. So, it would be best if you had a bunch of DevOps tools that can accelerate your software development lifecycle (SDLC.) The thing is, though, hundreds of tools can help you increase engineering productivity. Which ones to choose? That&amp;rsquo;s the million-dollar question. But worry no</description></item><item><title>Python Tutorial: 12. Putting it All Together - Merge Sort</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-12-putting-it-all-together-merge-sort/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-12-putting-it-all-together-merge-sort/</guid><description>Now that we finished learning about Python&amp;rsquo;s major quirks and features, let&amp;rsquo;s put it into action. Today, let&amp;rsquo;s see how to write a &amp;ldquo;sort&amp;rdquo; algorithm for lists. 1 Python Built-In Sort Recap As aforementioned in chapter 5 of this tutorial, Python lists have a built-in list.sort() method that modifies the list in-place. There is also a sorted() built-in function that builds a new sorted list from an iterable. sorted() returns</description></item><item><title>Python Tutorial: 11. Virtual Environments and Managing Packages with Pip</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-11-virtual-env-pip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-11-virtual-env-pip/</guid><description>Python apps and programs will often use packages and modules that don&amp;rsquo;t come as part of the standard library (stuff that is included in Python). Apps will sometimes need a specific version of a library, because the app may require that a particular bug has been fixed or the app may be written using an obsolete version of the library&amp;rsquo;s interface. This means it may not be possible for one</description></item><item><title>Python Tutorial: 10. Class</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-10-class/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-10-class/</guid><description>0 OOP and Classes To talk about class, we need to talk about Object-oriented programming (OOP) first. OOP is a programming paradigm based on the concept of &amp;ldquo;objects&amp;rdquo;, which can contain data and code: data in the form of fields (often known as attributes or properties), and code, in the form of procedures (often known as methods). The class provides a way of bundling data and functionality together. Creating a</description></item><item><title>Python Tutorial: 9. Error Handling</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-09-error-handling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-09-error-handling/</guid><description>We have only slightly mentioned error messages. If you have tried out some of the code examples yourself, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure you&amp;rsquo;ve met a few more errors and exceptions. Today, we will go over errors in general. There are (at least) two distinguishable kinds of errors: syntax errors exceptions 1 Syntax Errors Syntax errors, also known as parsing errors, are caused by incorrect syntax, or grammar. They are perhaps the</description></item><item><title>Python Tutorial: 8. Input and File Handling</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-08-input-output/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-08-input-output/</guid><description>There are several ways to present the output of a program; data can be printed in a human-readable form, or written to a file for future use. 1 Output Formatting Often you&amp;rsquo;ll want more control over the formatting of your output than using the print() function which simply prints space-separated values. There are several recommended ways to format output: 1.1 Formatted String Literals (Also called f-strings for short.) Begin a</description></item><item><title>Python Tutorial: 7. Modules - Organizing Code</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-07-code-organization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-07-code-organization/</guid><description>0 Background So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve been coding in the Python interpreter, which if we quit and re-enter, the functions and variables definitions we&amp;rsquo;ve made previously are lost. Therefore, if you want to write a somewhat longer program, you&amp;rsquo;d be better off using a text editor to prepare the input for the interpreter and running it with that file as input instead - which is known as creating a script. As</description></item><item><title>Python Tutorial: 6. Data Structures - Part 2</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-06-data-structures-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-06-data-structures-2/</guid><description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve mastered lists, let&amp;rsquo;s learn two more data structures that could change your world. 1 Sets A set (same as a mathematical set) is an unordered collection with no duplicate elements. Basic uses include membership testing (if something is in a group,) and eliminating duplicate entries (for example, if we convert a list to a set, duplicated items are eliminated because there can be no duplicates in a</description></item><item><title>Python Tutorial: 5. Data Structures</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-05-data-structures-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-05-data-structures-1/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s tutorial, we will go over some of the stuff we&amp;rsquo;ve already learned in more detail, and add some more new stuff as well. 1 More on Lists All of the methods of the list objects: list.append(x): add an item to the end of the list. list.extend(iterable): extend the list by appending all the items from the iterable. If you&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten about the iterable, see previous tutorials. list.insert(i, x):</description></item><item><title>Python Tutorial: 4. Functions</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-04-functions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-04-functions/</guid><description>1 Defining Functions We can create a function that writes the Fibonacci series to an arbitrary boundary (if you have forgotten about the Fibonacci series, refer to the second tutorial): &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; def fib(n): # write Fibonacci series up to n ... a, b = 0, 1 ... while a &amp;lt; n: ... print(a, end=&amp;#39; &amp;#39;) ... a, b = b, a+b ... print() ... &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; # Now call the function</description></item><item><title>Python Tutorial: 3. Flow Control</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-03-flow-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-03-flow-control/</guid><description>In the previous tutorial, we demonstrated the while statement, which is a &amp;ldquo;flow control&amp;rdquo; statement. In computer programming, control flow or flow of control is the order function calls, instructions, and statements are executed or evaluated when a program is running. In Python (as in most other programming languages,) there are more usual flow control statements than just while. 1 if Statements The most well-known flow control statement probably is</description></item><item><title>Python Tutorial: How to Learn Everything</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-pandas-excel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-pandas-excel/</guid><description>0 How to Learn Everything No matter what you&amp;rsquo;ve already known, chances are, there are still things that you don&amp;rsquo;t know. Learning Python isn&amp;rsquo;t drastically different. We&amp;rsquo;ve already learned quite a few basics in Python, but there is a lot of stuff we don&amp;rsquo;t know yet. Until now. Because today, we will learn &amp;ldquo;how to learn everything,&amp;rdquo; and we will learn by an example, which is to read Excel files</description></item><item><title>People Powered - Solid Action Items to Build Your Open-Source Community from Scratch</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/people-powered/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/people-powered/</guid><description>0 &amp;ldquo;People Powered&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; the Book Recently I read a book recommended by my boss: People Powered. A a good book, by any means. It explains what a community is and why you might need it. It categorizes communities into three different types and you can see to which type your project belongs. It teaches you how to write the value statements of your community. - It created a SCARF</description></item><item><title>AWS IAM Security Best Practices</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/iam-best-practice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/iam-best-practice/</guid><description>This blog is originally published on GitGuardian blog. Disclaimer: while this blogpost refers to AWS services in particular, the best practices are mostly the same for any other IAM framework &amp;ldquo;Security is job zero.&amp;rdquo; When it comes to security in AWS, this is the de facto culture and standard. It means, it&amp;rsquo;s even more important than any number one priority. At AWS, new services will not launch if there are</description></item><item><title>A Brief Introduction to Code Review: Everything You Want to Know</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/how-to-code-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/how-to-code-review/</guid><description>A Brief Introduction to Code Review: How-To Review GitHub Open-Source Code (And Everything Else)</description></item><item><title>Python Tutorial: 2. An Informal Introduction to Python</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-02-informal-intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-02-informal-intro/</guid><description>To repeat the examples in this tutorial, you must type everything after the prompt (&amp;raquo;&amp;gt;) in the interactive mode, when the prompt appears; lines that do not begin with a prompt are output from the interpreter. Note that a secondary prompt on a line by itself in an example means you must type a blank line; this is used to end a multi-line command. 0 Comments Start the interpreter and</description></item><item><title>Python Tutorial: 1. Getting Started</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-01-getting-started/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/python-01-getting-started/</guid><description>0 Whetting Your Appetite If you do a lot of work on computers, eventually, you will find that there&amp;rsquo;s some task you&amp;rsquo;d like to automate. For example, you may wish to perform a search-and-replace over a large number of text files, or rename and rearrange a bunch of photo files in a complicated way. Python is the language for you. Python is simple to use, but it is a real</description></item><item><title>A Brief History of the DMCA</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/dmca-takedowns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/dmca-takedowns/</guid><description>This article is orignally published at GitGuardian Blog. What is DMCA? The DMCA is short for the Digital Millennium Copyright Act. On Oct 12, 1998, the US Congress passed the DMCA, which amended U.S. copyright law to address important issues of the relationship between copyright and the internet. It was signed into law by President Clinton on Oct 28, 1998. What Exactly Does It Mean? I know, the term &amp;ldquo;DMCA&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>How To Setup Your Jenkins Pipeline in K8s with Git Secrets Leak Scan and Docker Image Scan</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/devsecops-jenkins-in-k8s-with-secret-scan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/devsecops-jenkins-in-k8s-with-secret-scan/</guid><description>This blog post is first published at GitGuardian blog. Disclaimer: this tutorial goes all the way through setting up Jenkins in a Kubernetes minikube cluster, if you&amp;rsquo;re only interested in the Jenkinsfile, jump to the last part! 0 GitGuardian and ggshield ggshield is a CLI application that runs in your local environment or in a CI environment to help you detect more than 350 types of secrets, as well as</description></item><item><title>On DevOps: 1. What It Is</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/on-devops-1-what-it-is/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/on-devops-1-what-it-is/</guid><description>Note: opinions are my own. They don&amp;rsquo;t represent my current company or any previous companies I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for. Note 2: recently, my colleague published a blog post (in Chinese, here&amp;rsquo;s the link if you are interested). I like this post, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to share more with you on the topic of DevOps. So I decided to publish a miniseries (7 episodes planned) on DevOps. Here&amp;rsquo;s the first article. Note</description></item><item><title>9 Extraordinary Terraform Best Practices That Will Change Your Infra World</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/9-terraform-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/9-terraform-best-practices/</guid><description>This article is orignally published at GitGuardian Blog. Before you quickly glance over the title and think &amp;ldquo;Oh god, yet another tutorial on how to give proper names to variables, how to use modules, how to manage states; nothing I haven&amp;rsquo;t already know&amp;rdquo; then close the tab right away, let me assure you this: this article is none of those. This &amp;ldquo;best practices&amp;rdquo; article aims to tell you something you</description></item><item><title>Dagger (the CI/CD Tool, not the Knife) In-Depth - Everything You Need to Know (as of Apr 2022)</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/dagger-in-depth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/dagger-in-depth/</guid><description>1 What is Dagger? TL;DR: Dagger runs your CI/CD pipelines locally in a Docker container, and can run the container in any CI environment (as long as that CI can run a container, of course.) Do you want the long answer to this million-dollar question? It&amp;rsquo;s hard to answer, honestly. News is calling it a &amp;ldquo;DevOps platform&amp;rdquo;; the VC that funded Dagger even called it a &amp;ldquo;DevOps operating system.&amp;rdquo; But,</description></item><item><title>Hello, World!</title><link>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.guotiexin.com/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>Hello, and welcome to the DevStream blog! In this very first &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; post, I will: give you a high-level picture of how DevStream functions; walk you through our codebase; explain briefly how to create your own plugin. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of DevStream yet, please have a quick glance over our README. Without further adieu, let&amp;rsquo;s get started. TL;DR Too bad, there isn&amp;rsquo;t one. But don&amp;rsquo;t close the tab</description></item></channel></rss>